This next collar style is a stand collar.
What we see this on typically would be like outer wear.
It could be on anything.
But like a jacket.
There you have a lapel, well not a lapel, this is one side of the jacket that comes over to this side of the jacket.
And the collar, as I said before a stand is the rise.
The stand is the length from there to there.
That's your collar stand.
So then obviously if you think about if for a minute, a stand collar is just that.
It's a separate piece attached to make a collar that just barely stands up from the actual garment itself.
And what you're going to want to show if it's a stand collar, and it needs to stand, it needs to have reinforcement.
Reinforcement is usually created by edge stitching, which are the dashed lines.
If this and this are the same fabric and you want this piece to stand up more, it just logically follows that you would have either that facing inside of it or you would edge stitch it to reinforce and make it stand up stiffer than the rest of the garment.